council member in the city's history for
nearly four decades councilman valenzue
has represented the columbia
neighborhood
[Applause]
[Music]
you look marvelous they're here as
always
it is my pleasure to be here and i
decided to say good evening my florida
does have to say good morning after a
while
and so we're going to get the show on
the road it is my pleasure to introduce
joe valencia before i say that i want to
congratulate all of you
president honorees and the former
honorees
what a wonderful group of people what a
wonderful organization
we should be very proud of the ethnic
and racial
history we have in the city of cleveland
and i want to thank and i i can be
remiss if i do not say to all of us we
see what's happening in europe and i
want to say to martha and our ukrainian
brothers and sisters and i'm going to
ask you all regardless of your faith to
pray for our ukrainian brothers and
sisters who are standing up to
hatred
genocide
brutality and standing up to a war
criminal we must never forget what we're
all about why our families came to this
country for freedom and democracy so my
ukrainian brothers and sisters god bless
you
i had a pleasure as well to sit next to
uh bishop
wurtz
and uh the new uh authority bishop of
cleveland i congratulations i've worked
him over a little bit over there so i
appreciate it and his um his vision for
our city what can i say about joe
blenson
when you think the slovenian community
and you were to look it up in a
dictionary the footnote would be
see joel
he's involved in every organization that
i could think of he's been a link
between slovenia and cleveland slovenia
and america
he is president
of the largest slovenian organization in
the united states he's president of the
cleveland federation of logistics
between the national federative society
number organization
you can hear him every saturday
on radio
he's been a producer
he's been involved in every type of
organization you can think of in every
slovenian event that i go to
i run into my friends
because he's never forgotten his roots
he's never forgotten where he came from
it's what my late dear friend diana
who was supposed to say to me all the
time
never forget where you came from
and never forget who you represent
joe
has never forgotten who he represents
and that's his
the biggest event on thanksgiving day
the poco hall of fame event
who runs it who was the past president
and now vice president joe malaysia
every place you look within the
slovenian community to see his name but
not only does he support the slovenian
he supports every other nationality
group there are all the other groups and
organizations because i go to i see joe
there
because he knows this is what cleveland
is
it's it's not it's not that melding
so often here
it is it is where we identify with each
one of our groups and our organizations
because he's there to support them
he's there to show his support so again
to my brothers and sisters who are
gathering it is my pleasure to introduce
an ether into cleveland international
hall of fame my friend
the dear dear supporter of the slovenian
community
[Applause]
it's so great to see so many friends
here this evening
bishop
uh mr griffin ms kendrick
and my slovenian past honorees august
post uh
dick russ there's also joe sipperman
25 years ago i served in the cleveland
bicentennial commission with dick pope
and al radner it was quite a time in the
city
to my fellow inductees it is an honor to
share this evening with you
your communities thrive because of your
efforts
thank you mike polencic for your
generous remarks mike is my councilman
and just like mike i am a lifelong
clevelander born and bred in north
college
now i love slovenia and i hope all of
you take a trip sometime to the sunny
side of the alps
but i am cleveland through and through
uh mike once asked me joe you like
slovenia so much
you know do you ever think of moving
there
and i said mike i can never do that they
don't have marks
cleveland loves to celebrate its bridges
just look outside whether they're real
ones over the cuyahoga or symbolic
bridges between countries cultures and
people
thank you to the board of the clinton
international hall of fame for
recommending me for this prestigious
award especially deborah hansen and dan
hansen
and inviting me to join so many
legendary individuals who have built
bridges between cleveland and the world
of course i can't do much by myself
none of us would be here without our
supporters our families our friends our
colleagues
on occasions like this evening my late
cousin dan irvington would say
i'm so glad my parents came to this
country
but i would add to that i'm so glad my
parents came to cleveland
well there are more slovenians in
cleveland than anywhere outside of
europe
i'm grateful to my family my parents
josephine and joe valencic
raised their three children in a
bilingual home and supported our
involvement in slovenian activities
many of you know my sister cecilia
dolgan now living in chicago
she was a dynamic leader within our
slovenian community and encouraged
consistently in my projects
she inspired so many including me
i also thank my late sister marianne
zeitz and my cousin helen hermanton who
is cheering me on at home
it's great to have my family and friends
here
and my shore acres
pals back here
kuala lumpur thank you to my family and
friends in stadium the old country in
slovenia
and then there are my fellow board
members at the national cleveland style
polka hall of fame and museum
[Applause]
[Music]
slovenians are such a small entity in
the mosaic of our country
but our gift to american culture is our
happy good time dance music what's known
as the cleveland style program
thank you team polka for preserving and
promoting promoting cleveland's own
sound
and my colleagues from the slovene
national benefits society at pj farm in
kirtland where
every summer sunday you can dance to
cleveland-style polka music
you're keeping the slovenian spirit
alive genio slovensi
i've been asked if i'm a professional
slovenian
um the pay is not much but the
camaraderie is present
i mean we're americans during the week
and slovenians on the weekend
like this evening's honorees i see
potentials within my community
i bring my professional skills to each
team i serve on to build interest and
awareness
to take advantage of strengths and make
connections
to encourage participation volunteers to
celebrate
to make it fun
i try to share my enthusiasm in what we
call that american can do
spirit cleveland has offered and still
offers so much to our nationality and
ethnic groups
take advantage of the opportunities
resources and technology available to
boost your cultural expressions to a new
life
create an engaging new event or an
online community fund a scholarship
mentor a young professional
keep connected to your roots whether
here or abroad
and build your communities bridges to
the future
thank you for this recognition
[Applause]
you